<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Home</title>
    
    
    <description>This website is a virtual proof that I&apos;m awesome</description>
    
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>P vs NP.</title>
        <description>
          Turing Machines and Complexity Clases. P vs NP asymmetry. - 
          0. Index. Introduction: Algorithms and Time Complexity. 1.1. Algorithms. 1.2. Time complexity. Solving problems and verifying solutions. 2.1. Problems. 2.2. Definitions. Languages, Decisions Problems, N/DTMs and Time in TMs. 2.2.1. Languages. 2.2.2. Decisions Problems and Languages. 2.2.3. Turing Machines. 2.2.4. Build a Turing machine that accepts a string and increments...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2026-01-11-PvsNP/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2026-01-11-PvsNP/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Race Conditions.</title>
        <description>
          Race Condition notes from OST2 course. - 
          1. Definition. 1.1. Race Condition definition. Race Condition is a term than refers to a set of bugs which arises when the behavior of a system depends on the relative timing or ordering of events, and that timing isn’t properly controlled. The “race” is between two or more operations that...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-12-28-RaceCondition/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-12-28-RaceCondition/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducción al Cálculo</title>
        <description>
          Ejemplos de ecuaciones matemáticas con LaTeX - 
          Teorema fundamental del cálculo La derivada de una integral es: \[\frac{d}{dx}\int_a^x f(t)dt = f(x)\] Ecuaciones inline También puedes usar ecuaciones dentro del texto, por ejemplo la famosa ecuación de Einstein $E = mc^2$ o la identidad de Euler $e^{i\pi} + 1 = 0$. Más ejemplos La fórmula cuadrática: \[x =...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-12-25-MathTest/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-12-25-MathTest/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Uninitialize Data Access.</title>
        <description>
          Uninitialice Data Access notes from OST2 course. - 
          1. Definition. 1.1. Preface. Initialize vs Uninitialize data. First, let’s introduce two memory regions in which the program data-storage happens at runtime, the stack and the heap. The stack is a LIFO structure in which fixed-size data within the function stackframe’s owner scope gets stored. The heap is an amount...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-12-23-UDA/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-12-23-UDA/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Control Flow.</title>
        <description>
          Unconditional and conditional x86-64 instructions. - 
          1. Control Flow. Definition and types. In terms of program execution; Control Flow is a term that refers in the order in which the instructions gets executed by the CPU. In normal conditions, there is a special non-general-purpouse register, the Instruction Pointer, (RIP/EIP/IP) which holds the address that points to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-12-12-ControlFlow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-12-12-ControlFlow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Other Integer Issues.</title>
        <description>
          Notes from Other Integer Issues course from OST2. - 
          1. Definition. This section is an extension about Integers Overflow issues. We are going to cover three topics: Incorrect Signed Sanity Checks. Signed or unsigned integer truncation. Signed Integer extension issues. 2. Incorrect Signed Sanity Checks. 2.1. Definition. Incorrect Signed Sanity Checks refers to the idea of bad sanity checks...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-12-05-OtherIntegerIssues/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-12-05-OtherIntegerIssues/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Integer Overflow/Underflow.</title>
        <description>
          Notes from Integer Overflow course from OST2. - 
          1. Integer Overflow/Underflow vulnerabilities introduction. Integer Overflow/Undwerflow vulnerabilities referer a vulnerability form in which an attacker leverage cases in which is possible that signed and unsigned integers exceeds their positive and negative value ranges due to egdy math cases. Before enter in a further explanation, let’s take a reminder on...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-12-05-IntegerOverflow-Underflow/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-12-05-IntegerOverflow-Underflow/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Passing Parameters.</title>
        <description>
          Calling Conventions and LEA instruction. - 
          1. Parameter Definition. First, a parameter is simply data that gets placed in a specific location where the calling convention dictates the callee should look for it. This means that is data that a called function knows where to find it. Consider the following code: int func(int a){ int i...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-12-04-Passing-Parameters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-12-04-Passing-Parameters/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stackframe; Local variables, Arrays and Structures.</title>
        <description>
          Assembly management of local variables, arrays and structures. - 
          1. Defintion. Let’s consider the following code: int calculate(int a, int b) { int result; int temp = 5; result = a + b + temp; return result; } int main() { int x = calculate(10, 20); return x; } We have a C code which returns a calculated value...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-12-01-LocalVars_Arrays_structs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-12-01-LocalVars_Arrays_structs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Out-Of-Bounds Write.</title>
        <description>
          Notes from Out-Of-Bounds Write course from OST2. - 
          1. Definition. In simple terms, Out-Of-Bounds Writes is a memory corruption vulnerability in which user-controlled data is used to calculate a memory location without proper security measures leading to data being write out of the intended destination in memory. In some ocasions user-controlled data can be written on a user-controlled...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-11-26-Out-Of-Bounds-Write/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-11-26-Out-Of-Bounds-Write/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Calling Functions.</title>
        <description>
          Introduction to CALL, RET, MOV, ADD and SUB instructions. - 
          1. Calling functions. In order to introduce some more instructions, lets consider the following C code int func(){ return 0xbeef; } int main() { func(); return 0xf00d; } and the corresponding Assembly tranlation: func: 0000000140001000 mov eax, 0BEEFh 0000000140001005 ret main: 0000000140001010 sub rsp, 28h 0000000140001014 call func (0140001000h) 0000000140001019...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-11-21-CallingFunctions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-11-21-CallingFunctions/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>(Linear) Heap Buffer Overflow.</title>
        <description>
          Notes from Heap Buffer Overflow course from OST2. - 
          1. Definition. A linear heap buffer overflow (LHBO), similar to an LSBO, occurs when an huge amount of data gets written in a heap-allocated buffer. By huge we mean an amount of data large enough to exceed the buffer size resulting in adyacents memory structures to be overwritten. A tipical...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-11-18-HBO/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-11-18-HBO/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Basic Instructions.</title>
        <description>
          Introduction to NOP, PUSH and POP instructions. - 
          1. Introduction. Assembly instruction definition. An assembly instruction is a human-readable representation of a machine code operation that a computer’s processor can execute. It’s a low-level programming command that directly corresponds to the binary instructions that the CPU understands. Basically they are mnemonic codes (like MOV, ADD, JMP) that represent...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-11-17-AssemblyBasicRegisters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-11-17-AssemblyBasicRegisters/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Computer Registers.</title>
        <description>
          Brief introduction to CPU Registers. - 
          1. Computer Memory Hierarchy. Computer memory hierarchy is a structured arrangement of different types of storage in a computer system, organized in terms of efficiency between speed access, capacity and availability. At the top there are the fastest but smallest in storage: CPU registers (directly inside the processor, nanosecond access)....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-11-08-ComputerRegisters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-11-08-ComputerRegisters/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CVE-2021-20294.</title>
        <description>
          Extended investigation about CVE-2021-20294 (unfinished). - 
          1. Introduction. This is an exploit for CVE-2021-20294. This vulnerability consists in a “linear stack buffer overflow” on the version 2.35 of binutils (downloaded from https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/binutils/binutils-2.35.tar.gz). static void print_dynamic_symbol (Filedata *filedata, unsigned long si, Elf_Internal_Sym *symtab, Elf_Internal_Shdr *section, char *strtab, size_t strtab_size) { const char *version_string; enum versioned_symbol_info sym_info; unsigned...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-11-07-CVE-2021-20294/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-11-07-CVE-2021-20294/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>(Linear) Stack Buffer Overflow.</title>
        <description>
          Notes from Stack Buffer Overflow course from OST2. - 
          1. Introduction. 1.1. Memory Layout. First of all, let’s introduce some fundamental concepts: Stack: The stack is the name of a data structure type where data is pushed onto the top and gets popped off the top. Exists a memory region which behaves like the stack data type and is...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-11-06-LSBO/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-11-06-LSBO/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Text Editor.</title>
        <description>
          Simple text exitor written in C. - 
          Creating a text editor: kilo. We are going to write a text editor in C. We are using the following Make file: kilo: kilo.c $(CC) kilo.c -o kilo -Wall -Wextra -pedantic -std=c99 We are declaring that we want to build ‘kilo’ binary from ‘kilo.c’. We are declaring the build command...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-08-11-Text-Editor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-08-11-Text-Editor/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Garbage Collector.</title>
        <description>
          Simple conservativer sweep-mark Garbage Collector. - 
          Garbage Collector. This is the second part, or the continuation from the previous report in which we build a custom memory allocator from a heap array. Now, we are going to pick up the code where we leave it and implement a garbage collector with several changes in the original...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-07-11-GarbageCollector/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-07-11-GarbageCollector/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hashtables.</title>
        <description>
          Explanation of hashtables in C. - 
          HashTables Presentation of the problem. Let’s suppose we have the following exercise: Given a roman numeral, convert it to an integer. The roman numbers are built through a finite set of simbols (Numerals) that have each equivalent decimal number as the following table shows: Roman Numeral Integer Value I 1...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-06-13-HashTable/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-06-13-HashTable/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building my own malloc in C.</title>
        <description>
          A malloc code written in C. - 
          Defining the idea. In this section we will built a custom malloc() function with also a free() and later a garbage collector. First, the central idea is that we are implementing a custom memory allocator along with a free function which will allocate and deallocate memory from a static array...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2025-06-09-BuildingOwnMalloc/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2025-06-09-BuildingOwnMalloc/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
